The Ultimate Experience in Inner Terror.
The Brood is a horror, science fiction film directed by David Cronenberg.
A man tries to uncover an unconventional psychologist's therapy techniques on his institutionalized wife, while a series
of brutal attacks committed by a brood of mutant children coincides with the husband's investigation.
Dr. Hal Raglan, played by Oliver Reed.
Nola Carveth, played by Samantha Eggar.
Frank Carveth, played by Art Hindle.
Barton Kelly, played by Henry Beckman.
Juliana Kelly, played by Nuala Fitzgerald.
Candice Carveth, played by Cindy Hinds.
The Brood is a 1979 Canadian psychological body horror film written and directed by
David Cronenberg, and starring Oliver Reed, Samantha Eggar, and Art Hindle.
Its plot follows a man and his mentally ill ex-wife, who has been sequestered by
a psychiatrist known for his controversial therapy techniques.
A series of brutal unsolved murders serves as the
backdrop for the central narrative.
Written by Cronenberg after his own acrimonious divorce, he intended the screenplay as a meditation on a fractured relationship
between a husband and wife who share a child, and cast Eggar and Hindle as loose facsimiles of himself and his ex-wife.
He would later state that, despite its incorporation of science fiction elements, he
considered it his sole feature that most embodied a "classic horror film".
Principal photography of The Brood took place in late 1978
in Toronto on a budget of $1.5 million.
The film's score was composed by Howard Shore.
Released in the spring of 1979 by New World Pictures, The Brood proved
profitable for the studio, grossing over $5 million.
Though it initially received mixed reviews from critics, it would
establish itself as a cult film in the following decades.
It has attracted scholarly interest from academics in the areas of film
theory for its themes regarding mental illness and parenthood.
In 2006, the Chicago Film Critics Association named it
the 88th scariest film of all time.
In 2013, it was selected for restoration by the Criterion
Collection, which subsequently released it on Blu-ray.
The film explores themes of toronto, canada, mutant,
transformation, psychologist, divorce.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.